# **Regina Furness**

Software Engineer with experience in Ruby and JavaScript based programming. My background in retail provided me with strong communication skills and the ability to take initiative and problem solve. Looking forward to a career working with other passionate people where I can both hone old skills and acquire new ones.

Fenton, MO 63026 (518) 669-2036 regina.furness2012@gmail.com





### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

React, Javascript, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, Ruby, HTML, CSS, SQL

#### **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

Problem Solving, Communication, Teamwork, Attention to Detail, Multitasking

### **EDUCATION**

# Flatiron School Software Engineering

April 2020 - October 2020 Full Stack Development Course

# Saranac Lake High School — Saranac Lake, NY

2012

High School Diploma

# **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Recipe-Tracker — Frontend Backend | Video Demo | Live

Recipe box application. Users have full CRUD functionality of recipes they submit. Users can view recipes submitted by other users.

- Coded frontend in React, bootstrapped with Create React App.
- Utilized Redux middleware to respond to and modify application state.
- Implemented Redux-Thunk middleware to communicate with Rails API server.
- Used React-Router for client-side routing.

# **Dottomodachi** — Github: Frontend Backend | Video Demo | Live

Virtual pixel pet mini game. Users can sign up to adopt multiple "dottomodachi" and are tasked with keeping their stats in an optimal range.

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage so a user can remain logged in between page refreshes.
- Created Rails API backend so information could be persisted and retrieved for use on the frontend.
- Used event listeners for a highly interactive user experience.
- Made use of Javascript classes to achieve more modular code.

## **DreamCatcher** — Github | Video Demo

Virtual Dream diary app. Users can create dream logs and choose whether to share them publicly or privately.

- Created application using Rails with full CRUD functionality.
- Incorporated Omniauth to allow users to sign up via Google.
- Employed Active Record validations to defend against invalid data being persisted to the database.
- Utilized BCrypt for secure password storage.

### **WORK HISTORY**

## Scan File Coordinator

Hannaford Supermarkets, Lake Placid NY

August 2018 - January 2020

- Implemented systems to cut payroll costs. Cut 40 hours from payroll by organizing and eliminating outdated price tags.
- Initiated new system for item price changes by department. Reducing staff time, allowing a more timely shift of focus to restocking and shelving.

# **Shift Supervisor**

Save-a-lot, Tupper Lake NY

November 2013 - August 2018

- Reduced shrink of bakery department 30% after taking over product ordering.
- Demonstrated leadership by taking on responsibilities outside of job description, eliminating the initial need to hire 2 additional staff members.